pse.com 2005-12-20

# Puget Sound Energy

**  
  
Last Revised: January 7, 2004**

Maintaining your privacy and trust are important to us at Puget Sound Energy (“PSE”). On this Web site (the “Site”), PSE collects information from you in connection with certain features and services. This privacy policy is designed to tell you how we collect and use personal information on this Site so that you can make an informed decision about using our Site. Please read this policy before using our Site or submitting any personal information to us. By using our Site, you consent to the information collection and use practices described in this policy. PSE reserves the right to change the provisions of this privacy policy at any time, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the privacy policy the date it was last updated. This posting constitutes PSE’s notice of any changes to this policy. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you visit our site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

PSE is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this policy.

Contents:

  1. What types of information are collected on this Site?  

  2. How does PSE use the information collected on this Site?  

  3. What information is shared with third parties?  

  4. What choices do I have in the use and collection of my information?  

  5. What steps does PSE take to protect my information?  

  6. How can I update or correct my personal information?  

  7. How do links affect my privacy?  

  8. How is the privacy policy updated?  

  9. Who can I contact with questions about this Site?

1\. What information is collected on this site?  
In order to provide you with certain services on our Site, we may need to collect different types of information. In particular, we occasionally may need to collect certain types of personal information (information that may be used to personally identify or contact you) in order to provide you with particular features, services, or offers. Here's a summary of the kinds of information we collect at the PSE Site, and how we collect that information:  

> **A. Passive Collection**  
>  Our software automatically collects certain information from your computer when you log on or move about our Site. This information is not linked to any other personal information you tell us, it just gives us a broad picture of who is on our Site and which areas your users are visiting. It is our way of learning what’s important to our users and what isn’t, and improving our Site to make it more interesting and useful for you. It also enables us to provide improved security and efficiency on our Site. The two main ways in which this general information is collected are through “log files” and “cookies.”
> 
> **(i) Log Files**  
>  Log files are records of user activity collected to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user’s movement, and gather broad types of information for aggregate use. The kinds of general information we collect in the log files includes: 
> 
>   * The IP address of your computer  
> 
>   * How many people visit our Site  
> 
>   * Which pages of our Site are visited most often  
> 
>   * Which ISPs our visitors come from (e.g. AOL, MSN, etc.)  
> 
>   * Which browsers users are used to visit our Site (Netscape, Internet Explorer, etc.)  
> 
>   * Time of day users visit our Site 
> 

> 
> **(ii) Cookies**  
>  PSE also uses “cookies” to gauge how users interact with our Site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Cookies cannot execute code or deliver a virus to your computer. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personally identifiable information, it merely helps the Site to be more efficient. Typically, a cookie enables your computer to load Web site files faster on subsequent visits. We also use cookies to track a user’s path for security purposes, as well as to target your interests in an effort to enhance your experience on our Site. If you wish to block, erase, or be warned of cookies, please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn about these functions. If you reject a cookie, you may still use our Site, however, you may be limited in your use of certain areas. Please note: some of our business partners (for example, advertisers) may use cookies on our Site and we have no access to or control over these cookies.
> 
> **B. Active Collection**  
>  At several places on our Site, we collect certain information that you voluntarily provide to us which may contain personally identifiable information (for example, your name, street and e-mail address, or telephone number). Such personally identifiable information could also include any other information you may provide when voluntarily participating in customer service contacts, surveys, or other transactions. Here is a brief summary of the areas on our Site where you may be asked to provide information:
> 
> **(i) Registration**  
>  One or more areas of our Site may require you to register for access. As part of the registration process we may ask you for a username, password, or other personally identifiable information in order to verify your identity, establish the account, promote security, and enable access to various online features. Information you give during registration online may also be linked to your energy account information in our system in order to provide you with simplified access to your account information online, or to provide other services to you related to your energy account.
> 
> **(ii) Online Customer Care Features**  
>  When using our online Customer Care Features we may ask for your address and account number just as we would if we were speaking to you over the phone or in person. We need to collect such personal information in order to furnish you with information about your account, generate reports based on your account usage, and provide services tailored to your personal account.
> 
> The following Customer Care areas of our site may involve your giving us personal information to process your requests and transactions: 
> 
>   * EnergyTracker Online Reports  
> 
>   * Energy In Business Online Reports  
> 
>   * Personal Energy Profile  
> 
>   * Business Energy Profile  
> 
>   * Voluntary Load Curtailment Service  
> 
>   * Contractor Referral Services  
> 
>   * Energy at Home e-Newsletter  
> 
>   * Energy In Business e-Newsletter  
> 
>   * Energy Efficient Services/Consulting 
> 

> 
> **(iii) Surveys and Contests**  
>  From time-to-time our site may request information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you have the choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use of and satisfaction with this site.
> 
> **(iv) Special Offers**  
>  We may send all new users a welcoming email to verify password and username. Users may occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and/or newsletters. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications (please see our choices in the use and collection of information section below). 
> 
> **(v) Site and Service Updates**  
>  We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Users are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We also communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email, phone, or postal mail.
> 
> **(vi) Nexus Energyguide**  
>  On certain co-branded pages, Nexus Energyguide may collect contact, demographic, energy use and other information from you on behalf of PSE. This information may allow you to create Energy Management Plans, sign up for electronic newsletters or use other tools or services. All information collected by Nexus Energyguide on behalf of PSE on such co-branded pages is the sole property of PSE and is governed by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Back to Top

2\. How Does PSE Use Information Collected on this Site?  
PSE is the sole owner of the information collected on this Site. Personal information that you provide to PSE (such as a personal e-mail address) may be used by PSE in the following ways: 

  * to contact you about your use of the Site or about our products and services;  

  * to respond to your comments or requests;  

  * to request feedback and enable us to develop and improve the Site and our products and services;  

  * for internal and marketing/promotional purposes; and  

  * for the specific purpose for which the information was provided. 

Back to Top

3\. What Information is Shared with Third Parties?  
We will not sell, share, or rent your personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this policy without first obtaining your authorization

We may disclose personal information you provide to independent contractors, service providers and consultants who are engaged by or working with PSE, consistent will all applicable laws and regulations. We may also use credit card processing companies to process payments for goods and services, outside shipping companies to ship orders and credit bureaus to check credit histories. We may partner with other parties to provide specific services and will share information with them in order to facilitate their provision of services. For example, when the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information necessary for the third party to provide these services. PSE may also contract with outside companies to administer our mailing lists or provide other services. Your personal information may be shared with an outside company for the sole purpose of administering the products, services and programs you have selected. PSE makes an effort to ensure, but does not guarantee, that all third party partners agree to the same high level of privacy safeguards that PSE itself provides to its users.

Additionally, we may share aggregated information (i.e. information we collect that does not allow you to be personally identified or contacted, for example demographic and site usage information) with third parties such as partners and advertisers without your authorization. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

As noted above, information collected by Nexus Energyguide on behalf of PSE on this Site or on co-branded pages is the sole property of PSE but may be used by Nexus Energyguide for the purpose(s) for which it was collected.

PSE reserves the right to share information with third parties if we are required to do so by law or if in our good faith judgment, such action is reasonably necessary to comply with the legal process, to respond to any claims, or to protect the rights of PSE, its customers, or the public.

Back to Top

4\. What choices do I have in the use and collection of my information?  
Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our services at the point where we ask for the information. Users who no longer wish to receive promotional e-mail materials from PSE may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to the e-mail with “unsubscribe” in the subject line, or e-mailing [customercare@pse.com](mailto:customercare@pse.com) and requesting to be taken off the list.

Back to Top

5\. What security precautions are taken to protect my information online?  
PSE takes reasonable precautions to protect our users' information. Physical, electronic and policy measures are in place to minimize the loss, misuse, or altering of any information we receive from you. When you are asked to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the advanced SSL encryption software. Encryption makes unauthorized access to the information much more difficult.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also take reasonable precautions to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. In fact, only certain employees are granted access to personally identifiable information. If you have any questions about the security at our Web site, you can send an email to [customercare@pse.com](mailto:customercare@pse.com) for more information.

Back to Top

6\. How do links affect my privacy?  
This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that PSE is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this Web site. Similarly, if you entered this Site through a link from another Web site, PSE is not responsible for or bound by the privacy policies or processes of that Web site.

Back to Top

7\. How can I update or correct my personal information?  
PSE has an interest in making sure that the information we do collect is accurate. Therefore, we strongly believe that our customers should have the ability to access and edit the personal information they have provided to us. To check, verify, correct or update the accuracy of you personally identifiable information please contact [ webmaster@pse.com](mailto:customercare@pse.com) or telephone (888) 225-5773 and ask for the Webmaster. Outside of the State of Washington, please call (425) 452-1234.

Back to Top

8\. How is the privacy policy updated?  
PSE reserves the right to change this privacy policy at any time. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes in an updated privacy policy so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. The effective date of the last revision is always posted at the top of the privacy policy. This posting constitutes PSE’s notice of any changes to this policy. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you visit our Site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

Back to Top

9\. Who can I contact with questions about this site?  
Questions or comments about PSE’s Site may be directed to the Puget Sound Energy at [ webmaster@pse.com](mailto:customercare@pse.com) or you may telephone us at (888) 225-5773 and ask for the Webmaster. From outside of the State of Washington, please call (425) 452-1234. You may also write to us at Webmaster, Puget Sound Energy, 10885 NE 4th Street, PO Box 97034, Bellevue, WA 98009-9734.

Back to Top
